somerset-care.com 2013-10-28

# Somerset Care Group | Privacy Policy

## Privacy and Security Policy 

#### 1\. Introduction 

Somerset Care Group is committed to both respecting your privacy and providing a secure website so your personal information is protected. You can be assured any information you provide to us will be used strictly in accordance with the terms laid out in this statement. 

#### 2\. Collecting Information 

We will only look to request necessary information from you and will only use and disclose this information in the course of applying for a job with Somerset Care Group, and to inform you of other services which we feel maybe appropriate to you. 

The information we hold will be, to the best of our knowledge, accurate and up to date. Under the Data Protection Act you have the right to see the personal information that we hold about you in our records. 

All personal information is treated confidentially and is safely stored on our computer, with security systems preventing unauthorised access. 

#### 3\. Confidentiality 

We will endeavour to treat all your personal information as private and confidential. Other than under the terms of this privacy statement we will not disclose any of your information to anyone. 

We would like to bring your attention to our obligations to disclose information in the following exceptional cases permitted by law. These are

  * Where we are legally forced to
  * Where there is a duty to the public to disclose information
  * Where you have given permission to disclose information
  * Where we have to protect our interest 

#### 4\. Information Security

How we protect your personal information from misuse and abuse is of great importance to us. We are constantly reviewing and enhancing our technical and physical security procedures to protect your personal data from unauthorised access. 

#### 5\. How Your Information Will Be Used 

Your information will be used for applying for a job within the Somerset Care Group. 

Somerset Care Group may use your information to keep you informed by post, telephone or email of products or services which may be of interest to you. 

#### 6\. Access To Your Information 

You can write to us at any time to obtain details of the information we hold about you. Please write to: 

Data Protection Officer   
Somerset Care Group   
Acacia House   
Blackbrook Park Avenue   
Taunton   
Somerset   
TA1 2PX 

Please quote your name, postal address and email address along with the details of your requirement. We will take reasonable steps to confirm your identity before providing you with details of any personal information we may hold about you. Therefore we would be grateful if you could provide two forms of identification such as a copy of a passport or driving license and a copy of a utility bill to confirm address. 

In accordance with the Data Protection Act, 1998 we are entitled to charge £10 to cover the administration costs involved with this process. Please make cheques payable to "Somerset Care Group".

#### 7\. How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

Cookie name | Cookie Description  
---|---  
__utma | This cookie is typically written to the browser upon the first visit to your site from that web browser. If the cookie has been deleted by the browser operator, and the browser subsequently visits your site, a new __utma cookie is written with a different unique ID. This cookie is used to determine unique visitors to your site and it is updated with each page view. Additionally, this cookie is provided with a unique ID that Google Analytics uses to ensure both the validity and accessibility of the cookie as an extra security measure.  
__utmb | This cookie is used to establish and continue a user session with your site. When a user views a page on your site the Google Analytics code attempts to update this cookie. If it does not find the cookie, a new one is written and a new session is established. Each time a user visits a different page on your site, this cookie is updated to expire in 30 minutes, thus continuing a single session for as long as user activity continues within 30-minute intervals. This cookie expires when a user pauses on a page on your site for longer than 30 minutes. You can modify the default length of a user session with the _setSessionCookieTimeout() method.      
  
__utmc | This cookie is no longer used by the ga.js tracking code to determine session status.  
  
__utmz | This cookie stores the type of referral used by the visitor to reach your site, whether via a direct method, a referring link, a website search, or a campaign such as an ad or an email link. It is used to calculate search engine traffic, ad campaigns and page navigation within your own site. The cookie is updated with each page view to your site.      
  
__utmv | This cookie is not normally present in a default configuration of the tracking code. the __utmv cookie passes the information provided via the _setVar() method, which you use to create a custom user segment. This string is then passed to the Analytics servers in the GIF request URL via the utmcc parameter. This cookie is only written if you have added the _setVar() method for the tracking code on your website page.      
  
__utmx | This cookie is used by Website Optimizer and only set when the Website Optimizer tracking code is installed and correctly configured for your pages. When the optimizer script executes, this cookie stores the variation this visitor is assigned to for each experiment, so the visitor has a consistent experience on your site.  See the Website Optimizer Help Center for more information.
